[
  {
    "id": "b842a9d9-1eb7-48fb-957d-b0cc40c58e29",
    "front": "**Def**: (especially of an old person) physically weak and thin. frailty N.\n**Farsi**: ضعیف، نحیف",
    "back": "frail (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "looks a bit frail."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6b03f6fc-a76f-42be-9c2c-cae909a8dfa5",
    "front": "**Def**: walks slowly and shakily because they are frail.\n**Farsi**: متزلزل، لرزان (معمولاً به دلیل پیری)",
    "back": "doddery (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "doddery walks slowly and shakily"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9b476e26-1852-4ec6-b1ae-9c55bbfac01a",
    "front": "**Def**: to make straight (form from straight + -en).\n**Farsi**: صاف کردن، راست کردن",
    "back": "straighten (V)",
    "examples": [
      "a brace to straighten her teeth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d640b2df-7f95-4252-a612-e76f9b156588",
    "front": "**Def**: the thing that makes you able to understand or achieve sth. SYN the secret of sth.\n**Farsi**: کلید، رمز اصلی (برای دستیابی به چیزی)",
    "back": "the key to sth (N)",
    "examples": [
      "The key to dressing for your body shape is to enhance your best features."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "80b716c4-61b4-4f96-a57b-6a71d54817c8",
    "front": "**Def**: increase or improve the quality, value, or status of sth.\n**Farsi**: بهبود بخشیدن، ارتقا دادن",
    "back": "enhance sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "The key to dressing for your body shape is to enhance your best features."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "52f400d1-2d11-4c27-a640-938eca190d6f",
    "front": "**Def**: a part of sb's face or body.\n**Farsi**: ویژگی، قسمت برجسته (صورت یا بدن)",
    "back": "feature (N)",
    "examples": [
      "enhance your best features"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "057fa96a-fa0a-4e83-8fc4-548c1e014691",
    "front": "**Def**: in a way that others will not notice. discreet ADJ. OPP indiscreet.\n**Farsi**: محتاطانه، به طور پنهانی",
    "back": "discreetly (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "discreetly conceal the not-so-good ones."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0e1e087b-01f3-4e54-8fb1-cefc64834742",
    "front": "**Def**: FML hide sth.\n**Farsi**: پنهان کردن، مخفی کردن",
    "back": "conceal sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "discreetly conceal the not-so-good ones."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e043b666-f8db-404e-9bb9-3c08aca92ee9",
    "front": "**Def**: information that can help you, e.g. to make a decision.\n**Farsi**: دستورالعمل، راهنما",
    "back": "guideline (N)",
    "examples": [
      "Here are a few guidelines."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6ede22be-63c2-44d2-b7ef-a1771112449d",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth which is false appear true.\n**Farsi**: توهم ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "create an illusion (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "vertical stripes will create the illusion of being slimmer."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3f19846f-7881-4475-814e-61ccded7ba23",
    "front": "**Def**: making sb look more attractive. OPP unflattering.\n**Farsi**: برازنده (لباس/آرایش)، خوشایند، تمجیدآمیز",
    "back": "flattering (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "That color is very flattering on you.",
      "The photo wasn't very flattering.",
      "He made some flattering remarks about her work."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "24b45add-6d31-40aa-ab5f-4f229fe905fe",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth seem bigger, better, worse, or more important than it really is. exaggeration N.\n**Farsi**: اغراق کردن، بزرگنمایی کردن",
    "back": "exaggerate sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "flattering because they exaggerate the length of the legs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "165829ec-c6cb-4982-9e3f-9ef8ca2ae9ed",
    "front": "**Def**: to make someone notice something.\n**Farsi**: جلب توجه کردن",
    "back": "draw attention to (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "jeans that sit below the waist are flattering, as they draw attention to the waistline."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3cd5d88e-00bd-4013-8d0b-d2956ddad0b9",
    "front": "**Def**: Do sth to make the waiter notice you.\n**Farsi**: جلب توجه کردن",
    "back": "attract attention (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "Attract the waiter's attention."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c19a4179-fd8e-4c58-b7fe-c8c672fc5db9",
    "front": "**Def**: He never listens to or considers what I say.\n**Farsi**: توجه کردن به، دقت کردن به",
    "back": "pay attention to (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "He never pays attention to me."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "85c716e5-4e90-4414-a538-c18d59ff3120",
    "front": "**Def**: make a decision about sth too quickly, before you have thought about all the facts. SYN leap to conclusions.\n**Farsi**: نتیجه‌گیری عجولانه کردن",
    "back": "jump to conclusions (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "if you jump to conclusions..."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fe270e3a-7bc4-404a-9447-f570bba14983",
    "front": "**Def**: a body movement you make to show a particular meaning.\n**Farsi**: ژست، حرکت بدن",
    "back": "gesture (N)",
    "examples": [
      "interpret a particular gesture"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "36ed151e-e101-492a-9a3a-546e1dd669e4",
    "front": "**Def**: If you misinterpret sth. you understand it wrongly.\n**Farsi**: بد تعبیر کردن، اشتباه فهمیدن",
    "back": "misinterpret sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "you may misinterpret what it means."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "58ca8832-9645-422f-9124-7271995fb08d",
    "front": "**Def**: the action or moment of looking into another person's eyes.\n**Farsi**: ارتباط چشمی",
    "back": "eye contact (N)",
    "examples": [
      "avoid eye contact"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d7c6f967-0e32-473b-818f-31329d6b6fde",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth is possibly true but is not always true.\n**Farsi**: لزوماً نه، نه الزاما",
    "back": "not necessarily (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "may not necessarily be lying"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5a3f0fc8-6591-4ffd-9f5b-240040913ad0",
    "front": "**Def**: FML see or notice sth; an observant person is good at noticing things. observation N.\n**Farsi**: مشاهده کردن، دیدن",
    "back": "observe sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "we need to observe a combination of behaviour"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "35689392-5efc-430b-af0e-9a164b36af99",
    "front": "**Def**: a mix of two or more things. combine v.\n**Farsi**: ترکیب، مجموعه",
    "back": "combination (N)",
    "examples": [
      "observe a combination of behaviour"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a5c3377-b51e-4545-a9b7-f71ac23d08cb",
    "front": "**Def**: show signs of sth, often a quality or a feeling. display N.\n**Farsi**: نمایش دادن، ابراز کردن",
    "back": "display sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "a combination of behaviour that a person displays."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9817903d-5648-4b98-b12e-ffb19bc9fe0d",
    "front": "**Def**: look and try to see or find sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: مراقب چیزی/کسی بودن، دنبال چیزی گشتن",
    "back": "look out for sth/sb (PHR V)",
    "examples": [
      "look out for any or all of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ca9b1f67-dfdd-4f14-bb61-dde8a0d92e6a",
    "front": "**Def**: become red in the face, often when you're angry or embarrassed.\n**Farsi**: سرخ شدن (از خجالت یا عصبانیت)",
    "back": "go red (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "going red"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "781dff63-d82e-46cd-8057-54c6f4d8e7e7",
    "front": "**Def**: If you sweat, water appears on the surface of your skin because you are hot. SYN perspire FML.\n**Farsi**: عرق کردن",
    "back": "sweat (V)",
    "examples": [
      "sweating a lot"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3452d60d-0121-4698-814a-e9d6122860cb",
    "front": "**Def**: more than is reasonable or necessary. excess N. exceed v.\n**Farsi**: بیش از حد، مفرط",
    "back": "excessive (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "excessive hand gestures."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bcb9f755-3666-4a7e-8d27-41687c672d9a",
    "front": "**Def**: remember to consider sth.\n**Farsi**: در نظر داشتن، به خاطر سپردن",
    "back": "bear sth in mind (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "bear in mind the danger of making generalizations"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ab9a7cb3-9af5-4785-8818-4dcce0db0462",
    "front": "**Def**: make general statements about sth that may only be based on a few examples. generalize v.\n**Farsi**: کلی‌گویی کردن",
    "back": "make generalizations about sth (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "making generalizations about body language"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "651c695d-265e-4cff-a35d-1782302bdc01",
    "front": "**Def**: suggest that you feel or think sth without saying so directly. implication N.\n**Farsi**: اشاره ضمنی کردن، دلالت داشتن",
    "back": "imply sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "folded arms may imply stubbornness."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4f244358-96bb-417c-8614-62440692999c",
    "front": "**Def**: a determination not to change your opinion or attitude. SYN obstinacy.\n**Farsi**: لجبازی، سرسختی",
    "back": "stubbornness (N)",
    "examples": [
      "folded arms may imply stubbornness."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "34ad10df-df20-4b9a-b949-b2a0167a461e",
    "front": "**Def**: INF be attracted to sb.\n**Farsi**: کسی را دوست داشتن، از کسی خوش آمدن (جذب شدن)",
    "back": "fancy sb (V)",
    "examples": [
      "Women who fancy someone often smile more.",
      "I think he fancies you.",
      "Do you fancy a drink tonight?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "18a70bab-ab55-4565-9760-07189d8401fa",
    "front": "**Def**: keep moving or touching sth with your hands.\n**Farsi**: ور رفتن با چیزی، دستکاری کردن",
    "back": "fiddle with sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "Women often fiddle with their hair"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "566a740e-76f3-42bf-868a-84a431225636",
    "front": "**Def**: move your hand or fingers gently over the surface of sth.\n**Farsi**: نوازش کردن، دست کشیدن",
    "back": "stroke sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "men stroke an earlobe."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7dffaaa9-6463-49c1-9f43-43c60d426ed1",
    "front": "**Def**: behave towards sb as if you find them sexually attractive, but not in a serious way.\n**Farsi**: لاس زدن، عشوه آمدن",
    "back": "flirt (with sb) (V)",
    "examples": [
      "neck when they're flirting."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "04a3de63-49b2-4a8d-81d3-c9f79d8ade5f",
    "front": "**Def**: move slowly and quietly so you are not seen or heard. (also tiptoe).\n**Farsi**: خزیدن، دزدکی رفتن",
    "back": "creep (V)",
    "examples": [
      "I crept up the stairs, so that I wouldn't wake anyone."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7f28775b-7e7a-4acb-ae11-881b70e2bb56",
    "front": "**Def**: walk casually for pleasure.\n**Farsi**: قدم زدن، گشت زدن",
    "back": "stroll (V)",
    "examples": [
      "We strolled along the beach."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "010590f1-8c69-41e9-b6e9-faf44b520ca0",
    "front": "**Def**: walk slowly and with difficulty because one leg or foot is injured.\n**Farsi**: لنگیدن",
    "back": "limp (V)",
    "examples": [
      "He limped quite badly after his accident."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "412e0670-88c1-49fa-a44e-be89207bd3f8",
    "front": "**Def**: walk with difficulty, being almost unable to stand up.\n**Farsi**: تلوتلو خوردن",
    "back": "stagger (V)",
    "examples": [
      "he staggered to the nearest house and phoned for help."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a76a5bab-03b3-49dc-adc9-ff8646ba0d7b",
    "front": "**Def**: walk long distances in the country.\n**Farsi**: پیاده‌روی طولانی کردن (در طبیعت)",
    "back": "hike (V)",
    "examples": [
      "They hiked across the countryside."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5baf4080-2192-45c6-a427-5e0b3a540656",
    "front": "**Def**: walk with stiff regular steps.\n**Farsi**: رژه رفتن، با قدم‌های منظم راه رفتن",
    "back": "march (V)",
    "examples": [
      "The soldiers marched for over 20 kms."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d2c46c4f-d2a3-43aa-8b34-c9a983ea846f",
    "front": "**Def**: run, drive, etc. after sb/sth to catch them.\n**Farsi**: تعقیب کردن",
    "back": "chase sb/sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "Police chased the man for miles."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3af5ece5-f3b0-4093-b359-4aef894173bc",
    "front": "**Def**: run quickly and suddenly.\n**Farsi**: با سرعت دویدن",
    "back": "dash (V)",
    "examples": [
      "I dashed across the road for the bus."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4c9fece7-b00e-410c-81cf-fbae1f3ee573",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a horse or rider) run quickly.\n**Farsi**: تاختن، چهارنعل رفتن (اسب)",
    "back": "gallop (V)",
    "examples": [
      "The horse galloped across the field."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2012d70a-ee56-4c1e-9f1a-201de07ab690",
    "front": "**Def**: move quickly in a particular direction, often to attack sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: یورش بردن، حمله کردن",
    "back": "charge (V)",
    "examples": [
      "An angry section of the crowd charged towards the security men."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7f39c7f8-34cd-4464-8b69-0375221b8bbe",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of physical exercise you do to keep fit. work out v.\n**Farsi**: تمرین ورزشی",
    "back": "workout (N)",
    "examples": [
      "My 20-minute workout"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f01d7149-3be7-4ffa-9fbe-05f669d36321",
    "front": "**Def**: able to bend and move parts of your body easily.\n**Farsi**: نرم، منعطف",
    "back": "supple (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm not as supple or agile as I used to be."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "59bcb0ee-255e-4cf5-9400-d11161d980e3",
    "front": "**Def**: able to move quickly and easily. agility N.\n**Farsi**: چابک، فرز",
    "back": "agile (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm not as supple or agile as I used to be."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "18c83666-4954-4979-a232-4d6450f61f7e",
    "front": "**Def**: feeling some pain and unable to move easily. stiffness N.\n**Farsi**: خشک، سفت (بدن)",
    "back": "stiff (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I was beginning to feel quite stiff and sluggish."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d3ebb973-eccb-404c-bbb1-50c9ff243d4a",
    "front": "**Def**: moving slowly, below your normal activity level. sluggishness N.\n**Farsi**: کند، تنبل",
    "back": "sluggish (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I was beginning to feel quite stiff and sluggish."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ac6fc36e-1828-45f0-9d5a-5e137e6e622d",
    "front": "**Def**: invent a method or plan of doing sth. SYN think sth up.\n**Farsi**: ابداع کردن، طرح ریختن",
    "back": "devise sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "asked a friend to devise a workout routine."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a79e1373-9e91-4097-8fdf-3a11962274d3",
    "front": "**Def**: do physical activities to prepare the muscles for exercise. SYN warm up.\n**Farsi**: بدن را گرم کردن، نرمش کردن",
    "back": "loosen up (PHR V)",
    "examples": [
      "First I loosen up with some stretching."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "df888d4f-7d82-4850-a203-45142f565d4a",
    "front": "**Def**: lean over at the waist (also bend your knee, elbow, etc.).\n**Farsi**: خم شدن",
    "back": "bend (V)",
    "examples": [
      "bending"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "743ccaae-07ae-4eba-bbdc-fb27764d0dbe",
    "front": "**Def**: needing effort and energy. SYN arduous.\n**Farsi**: سخت، طاقت‌فرسا",
    "back": "strenuous (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "then I go on to something more strenuous."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5d548ec5-5a60-44dd-8daf-8bad052de5eb",
    "front": "**Def**: A thing that is relentless never seems to stop or get any easier.\n**Farsi**: بی‌وقفه، سخت و بی‌امان",
    "back": "relentless (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I find them relentless."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1a9cc6cb-ffd1-4383-8590-1e8d69cc9cf2",
    "front": "**Def**: happening or appearing again and again. recur v.\n**Farsi**: مکرر، عودکننده",
    "back": "recurrent (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I also have a recurrent elbow problem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "42d161a1-063a-4ce6-bde6-47256d72c721",
    "front": "**Def**: do A. then B, then do A again, and so on.\n**Farsi**: بین دو چیز متناوب عمل کردن",
    "back": "alternate between A and B (V)",
    "examples": [
      "I prefer to alternate between jogging and sprinting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "352e3f53-553a-45b0-9dfd-ec8f84c4b48c",
    "front": "**Def**: run a short distance very fast.\n**Farsi**: با حداکثر سرعت دویدن",
    "back": "sprint (V)",
    "examples": [
      "alternate between jogging and sprinting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "00425c1c-0414-4c33-891c-d66a39f815fe",
    "front": "**Def**: happening all the time or a lot of the time.\n**Farsi**: ثابت، دائم، پیوسته",
    "back": "constant (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "There were constant interruptions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf928ac5-c531-4d4a-9f03-a580080a511a",
    "front": "**Def**: make or cause sth to make short, loud sounds. rattle N.\n**Farsi**: تق‌تق کردن، به صدا درآوردن",
    "back": "rattle (V)",
    "examples": [
      "The windows rattled in the wind"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "06f7bc57-6860-414f-956d-9eca70880fae",
    "front": "**Def**: a long, deep sound or series of sounds. rumble v.\n**Farsi**: غرولند، صدای عمیق و طولانی",
    "back": "rumble (N)",
    "examples": [
      "a distant rumble of thunder."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ef18f91d-35a5-4ba4-912a-5effc2c6d2d3",
    "front": "**Def**: make or cause sth to make a noise like paper, leaves, etc. rubbing together. rustle N.\n**Farsi**: خش‌خش کردن",
    "back": "rustle (V)",
    "examples": [
      "Trees rustled"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4ac7f231-2b11-49ff-90f2-b371b053c180",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a liquid) fall onto sth in large drops and make it wet. splash N.\n**Farsi**: پاشیدن (مایع)، صدای چلپ چلوپ دادن",
    "back": "splash on/onto sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "big raindrops splashed onto the windows."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1cf0e89c-2557-472a-bfc2-53d036a4027f",
    "front": "**Def**: If a car horn beeps it makes a short high or loud sound. beep N.\n**Farsi**: بوق زدن، صدای بوق دادن",
    "back": "beep (V)",
    "examples": [
      "someone beeped their horn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b71fb0ef-1b75-48ef-8208-08bd25f9ecd5",
    "front": "**Def**: a loud, high, unpleasant sound. screech v.\n**Farsi**: جیغ، صدای بلند و ناخوشایند",
    "back": "screech (N)",
    "examples": [
      "a screech of brakes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eb22f2de-7fb7-455f-ae8a-98dffa9fdd39",
    "front": "**Def**: shut sth with a lot of force so that it makes a loud noise.\n**Farsi**: محکم بستن (در)",
    "back": "slam sth (shut) (V)",
    "examples": [
      "Someone slammed the car door shut."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bde68238-34c1-4083-b68e-fdfac31f9017",
    "front": "**Def**: make a wet, sucking sound, e.g. when you walk through mud.\n**Farsi**: صدای چلپ و چلوپ کردن (در گل)",
    "back": "squelch (V)",
    "examples": [
      "footsteps squelched through the mud"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9f839aa5-f1f7-43a8-8b24-e9f4996393c3",
    "front": "**Def**: make the sound that an old door or floor makes. creak N.\n**Farsi**: جیرجیر کردن",
    "back": "creak (V)",
    "examples": [
      "a floorboard on the stairs creaked"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a9f8abbd-6d9d-4171-8f39-e7a9a38cf801",
    "front": "**Def**: (of sounds) very high in the register of sound. OPP low-pitched.\n**Farsi**: زیر، با صدای نازک",
    "back": "high-pitched (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "a high-pitched scream"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3ff93036-1e67-4662-938c-6b984e6901bb",
    "front": "**Def**: (dogs) make a short loud sound. (Human behavior: boss's bark is worse than his bite = He's not really as angry or aggressive as he sounds.)\n**Farsi**: پارس کردن (سگ)",
    "back": "bark (N/V)",
    "examples": [
      "My boss's bark is worse than his bite."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "17e0c92f-dce6-4b92-b493-be24efc52d28",
    "front": "**Def**: (wolves) make a long loud cry. (Human behavior: howling in pain, howled with laughter.)\n**Farsi**: زوزه کشیدن (گرگ)، با صدای بلند گریه/خندیدن",
    "back": "howl (N/V)",
    "examples": [
      "The audience howled with laughter."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cc61c2a0-d32a-4518-a043-18c328690ad7",
    "front": "**Def**: (dogs) make a deep, angry sound. (Human behavior: said in a low, angry voice. SYN snarl.)\n**Farsi**: غرولند کردن (سگ)، با صدای خشمگین حرف زدن",
    "back": "growl (V)",
    "examples": [
      "'What are you doing here?' he growled."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "71776a02-8d17-4047-be01-e421e9d5c73b",
    "front": "**Def**: (bees) make a continuous low sound. (Human behavior: head was buzzing = thinking about it continuously, buzzing about = moving around continuously.)\n**Farsi**: وِزوِز کردن (زنبور)، فکر در سر چرخیدن",
    "back": "buzz (V)",
    "examples": [
      "I was buzzing about all day."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e28614b7-2c3c-4a86-9758-c8046f4481e9",
    "front": "**Def**: (lions) make a very loud deep sound. (Human behavior: a huge roar when Drogba scored, roared with laughter.)\n**Farsi**: غرش کردن (شیر)، فریاد/خنده بلند کردن",
    "back": "roar (N/V)",
    "examples": [
      "We roared with laughter."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "214b62d6-054a-4c5b-b9d2-4bc01a75444c",
    "front": "**Def**: (mice) make a short high but not loud sound. (Human behavior: squeaked down the phone = spoke in a high-pitched, excited voice. squeaky ADJ.)\n**Farsi**: جیرجیر کردن (موش)، با صدای زیر هیجان‌زده صحبت کردن",
    "back": "squeak (V)",
    "examples": [
      "'I've won the cup!' she squeaked down the phone."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c01143d0-3a44-4d96-9dd2-cb0f9a3ef8ad",
    "front": "**Def**: (cocks) make repeated loud sounds especially in the morning. (Human behavior: crowing about = talking too proudly about. SYN boast.)\n**Farsi**: قوقولی‌قوقو کردن (خروس)، لاف زدن (با غرور حرف زدن)",
    "back": "crow (V)",
    "examples": [
      "He was crowing about his victory all night."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b40ed67b-b965-432a-a9ac-c27123ebcd01",
    "front": "**Def**: (owls) make a long 'oo' sound. (Human behavior: hooted at me = sounded her car horn, hots of derision.)\n**Farsi**: هو کردن (جغد)، بوق زدن (ماشین)، هو کردن (تمسخر)",
    "back": "hoot (V)",
    "examples": [
      "There were hoots of derision from the audience."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "964bec77-ba56-4a2c-ac86-3cd5c876065c",
    "front": "**Def**: the ability to see. SYN sight.\n**Farsi**: بینایی، قدرت دید",
    "back": "eyesight (N)",
    "examples": [
      "poor eyesight."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "10e831c7-26d0-4b5d-88c6-aa47c20460d9",
    "front": "**Def**: a slight pain in your eyes, e.g. from reading a lot.\n**Farsi**: خستگی چشم",
    "back": "eye strain (N)",
    "examples": [
      "eye strain is a common complaint."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "71c47f42-7f81-45ab-bfda-238764974129",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of slight pain.\n**Farsi**: ناراحتی، عدم آسایش",
    "back": "discomfort (N)",
    "examples": [
      "discomfort is a common complaint."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "66f84681-5523-404e-b7fe-6b84d82cef9f",
    "front": "**Def**: If your vision is blurred you cannot see clearly.\n**Farsi**: تاری دید",
    "back": "blurred vision (N)",
    "examples": [
      "blurred vision are common complaints."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fa5cfd91-f55d-4347-968d-53492afebfb8",
    "front": "**Def**: shut and open your eyes quickly.\n**Farsi**: پلک زدن",
    "back": "blink (V)",
    "examples": [
      "blink often to keep your eyes moist."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "446b1bb5-e6e6-4ba7-9b94-d40d232155fe",
    "front": "**Def**: a drop of liquid that comes out of your eye when you cry.\n**Farsi**: اشک",
    "back": "tear (N)",
    "examples": [
      "poor tear production"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "165b031f-e67f-4bce-8738-9e4c3284f3bf",
    "front": "**Def**: painful, red, or swollen. irritation N.\n**Farsi**: تحریک شده، ملتهب",
    "back": "irritated (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "dry, irritated eyes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "81648ad7-71a0-478c-a968-e7fc6a76f532",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth less unpleasant or painful. SYN alleviate sth.\n**Farsi**: تسکین دادن، کاهش دادن",
    "back": "ease sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "ease your discomfort"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9d00181d-2088-458a-b548-9a88a4b91a70",
    "front": "**Def**: change sth slightly to make it more suitable. adjustment N.\n**Farsi**: تنظیم کردن، تطبیق دادن",
    "back": "adjust sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "adjust your computer screen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0cd8fce3-a05b-47c0-90a6-ae1d3a7e3f92",
    "front": "**Def**: remove or get rid of sth. elimination N.\n**Farsi**: حذف کردن، از بین بردن",
    "back": "eliminate sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "eliminate glare"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8b885223-6454-4274-9ee0-8607d1cd9b16",
    "front": "**Def**: a bright, unpleasant light.\n**Farsi**: تابش خیره‌کننده، نور آزاردهنده",
    "back": "glare (N)",
    "examples": [
      "adjust lighting to eliminate glare"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "53a0adc8-cc99-42f5-ad50-98f72efefd19",
    "front": "**Def**: slightly wet, often in a way that is useful or pleasant.\n**Farsi**: مرطوب",
    "back": "moist (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "keep your eyes moist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a5812bcf-66de-480a-b316-44522c92ffec",
    "front": "**Def**: A person who can see very little.\n**Farsi**: کم‌بینا",
    "back": "partially sighted (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "A partially sighted person can see very little."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "69fa2bce-80fc-439d-8d5e-57e2885af3ba",
    "front": "**Def**: look at sth for a long time because you are interested in it or are thinking about sth else. gaze N.\n**Farsi**: خیره شدن، با دقت نگاه کردن",
    "back": "gaze at sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "gazing at the breathtaking view below."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3307007c-b243-467c-a616-f8735dda579e",
    "front": "**Def**: very impressive. SYN spectacular.\n**Farsi**: نفس‌گیر، شگفت‌انگیز",
    "back": "breathtaking (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "gazing at the breathtaking view below."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d41b3442-5c9c-4d8b-ab8c-f41a4d974db3",
    "front": "**Def**: only with great difficulty or effort. SYN only just.\n**Farsi**: به سختی، به زور",
    "back": "barely (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "the port was barely visible"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ea36d3cc-099b-4bda-9320-b6bd64e545a3",
    "front": "**Def**: A thing that is visible can be seen. OPP invisible.\n**Farsi**: قابل دید، مرئی",
    "back": "visible (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "the port was barely visible"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c9eb894-c7d2-47ad-a146-e827ac1c86b6",
    "front": "**Def**: smoke, dust, or mist in the air which is hard to see through. hazy ADJ.\n**Farsi**: مه رقیق، غبار",
    "back": "haze (N)",
    "examples": [
      "through the early morning haze."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bbb8ad68-37f6-4300-aed1-da8c13b6fd1b",
    "front": "**Def**: see, hear, or understand sth/sb with difficulty.\n**Farsi**: تشخیص دادن، متوجه شدن",
    "back": "make sth/sb out (PHR V)",
    "examples": [
      "we could just make out the island."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e4fe4b09-7b3a-462c-8408-8bd1f8b146d0",
    "front": "**Def**: appear. OPP disappear from view/sight.\n**Farsi**: در معرض دید قرار گرفتن، پدیدار شدن",
    "back": "come into view/sight (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "a deer came into view"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b06f91e9-44b9-4dca-84d1-eeb266b5b8bc",
    "front": "**Def**: stand without moving (also keep/stay/sit still).\n**Farsi**: ثابت ایستادن، بی‌حرکت ماندن",
    "back": "stand still (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "They stood completely still"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4085a6f4-95e9-4bae-a6dd-94894d09fcec",
    "front": "**Def**: look at sb/sth carefully or because you are suspicious of them/it.\n**Farsi**: زیر نظر گرفتن، نگاه کردن (با سوءظن)",
    "back": "eye sb/sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "eyeing us warily"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "32e1d754-ecce-4404-8b21-65b4cb540d1d",
    "front": "**Def**: carefully, because you think there may be danger or a problem.\n**Farsi**: با احتیاط، محتاطانه",
    "back": "warily (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "eyeing us warily"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e5ce5a0b-1b36-489d-a341-efba6eeed4f0",
    "front": "**Def**: disappear suddenly or in a way you cannot explain.\n**Farsi**: غیب شدن، ناپدید شدن",
    "back": "vanish into thin air (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "ran off and vanished into thin air."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "be8cba32-4c52-454c-90ae-93329e362fa4",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them for a very short time and not clearly or completely.\n**Farsi**: لحظه‌ای دیدن، نگاهی اجمالی انداختن",
    "back": "catch a glimpse of sth/sb (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "We caught a glimpse of the actress."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "777b6095-2e0c-428b-a294-38aabe01fbd2",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them suddenly, often when you have been hoping to see them.\n**Farsi**: ناگهان دیدن، چشمش به چیزی افتادن",
    "back": "catch sight of sb/sth (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "She caught sight of her cousin in the crowd."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a06eee0-3fda-4a07-b362-70cef993cd96",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them suddenly, especially when they are hard to see.\n**Farsi**: ناگهان دیدن (در شرایط دشوار)",
    "back": "spot sb/sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "I spotted several mistakes in my work."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b55a58dd-7a90-4262-9c94-548d49e07af1",
    "front": "**Def**: rub or knead the body’s muscles.\n**Farsi**: ماساژ دادن",
    "back": "massage (V/N)",
    "examples": [
      "Massage the scalp vigorously."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f0449857-ad07-46c4-9869-3d130c05c6b4",
    "front": "**Def**: move or make sth move easily over a smooth or wet surface.\n**Farsi**: لغزیدن، سُر خوردن",
    "back": "slide (V)",
    "examples": [
      "sliding steadily up and over the forehead."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5a38e125-7159-475b-873c-f8efbdf21e32",
    "front": "**Def**: press on sth hard with your hand, foot, etc.\n**Farsi**: فشار وارد کردن",
    "back": "apply pressure to sth (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "Apply gentle pressure to the temples."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a14cadd6-89c2-4891-904d-3de8c3d1a6a8",
    "front": "**Def**: make a part of the body or skin more active.\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن",
    "back": "stimulate sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "Stimulate the skin by gently patting the cheeks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "29830eee-561d-478c-b24a-638ff4965c12",
    "front": "**Def**: touch sth lightly several times with your hand flat.\n**Farsi**: ضربه آرام زدن، دستمالی کردن (آرام)",
    "back": "pat sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "gently patting the cheeks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1435a2ac-1c56-4260-9dc7-e8068e1d4cd6",
    "front": "**Def**: hold sth tightly between the thumb and finger.\n**Farsi**: نیشگون گرفتن",
    "back": "pinch sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "lightly pinch the skin along the line of the jaw."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "34d85fb8-f595-4e44-89cd-e5322af2045b",
    "front": "**Def**: the feeling you have if your muscles are tight and not relaxed (release the tension = allow or cause the muscles to relax).\n**Farsi**: تنش، گرفتگی عضلانی",
    "back": "tension (N)",
    "examples": [
      "To release tension around the eyes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "12de5e5c-b0a1-4c34-a1e2-a03f2221fb63",
    "front": "**Def**: press sth firmly with your fingers.\n**Farsi**: فشار دادن، چلاندن",
    "back": "squeeze sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "firmly squeeze the eyebrows with your fingertips."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ead84e5b-7190-4702-904c-59ca0d55cf35",
    "front": "**Def**: describe soft, relaxed movements.\n**Farsi**: به آرامی، ملایم",
    "back": "gently (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "Start by gently stroking the whole face."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1e7f5c13-ab79-48be-b922-9b8c5db280c6",
    "front": "**Def**: describe soft, relaxed movements.\n**Farsi**: به آرامی، سبک",
    "back": "lightly (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "Use your fingertips to lightly pinch the skin."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "780667da-1efe-4c3c-8716-a5b149b19877",
    "front": "**Def**: with much stronger force.\n**Farsi**: محکم، قاطعانه",
    "back": "firmly (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "firmly squeeze the eyebrows."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "36b16fbc-d429-41ae-a400-5d2047665fa9",
    "front": "**Def**: regular, controlled movements.\n**Farsi**: پیوسته، با ثبات",
    "back": "steadily (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "sliding steadily up and over the forehead."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8bfa6edd-54b2-4d9a-a342-25d60571bfc3",
    "front": "**Def**: in a very energetic and active way. SYN energetically.\n**Farsi**: پرانرژی، با قدرت",
    "back": "vigorously (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "Massage the scalp vigorously."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a000966-2d6c-410d-b880-c4aa7de71806",
    "front": "**Def**: light and pleasant. SYN subtle.\n**Farsi**: طعم/عطر لطیف",
    "back": "delicate flavour/fragrance (N)",
    "examples": [
      "What a delicate flavour/fragrance."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d92edd1b-fbf6-4716-9a51-298b0e377c6a",
    "front": "**Def**: a pleasant smell. fragrant ADJ.\n**Farsi**: عطر، بوی خوش",
    "back": "fragrance (N)",
    "examples": [
      "What a delicate fragrance."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ae7570b1-2039-4aab-aa99-be01804635ac",
    "front": "**Def**: just possible to smell, see, or hear.\n**Farsi**: ضعیف، کم‌رنگ",
    "back": "faint (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "It has a faint smell of pear."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "43ba693b-608a-44c0-adf3-634de6b080cf",
    "front": "**Def**: making you feel hungry. OPP unappetizing.\n**Farsi**: اشتها‌آور",
    "back": "appetizing (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "lots of appetizing recipes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9aceb02d-6843-4d60-b8f2-351d5a4351a6",
    "front": "**Def**: If your mouth waters, you produce saliva and want to eat. mouth-watering ADJ.\n**Farsi**: آب دهان راه افتادن، هوس کردن",
    "back": "mouth water (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "The smells... were making my mouth water."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e6e8483-1290-4a4d-b84e-7b02dd60744e",
    "front": "**Def**: a pleasant, distinctive smell.\n**Farsi**: عطر، بوی مطبوع",
    "back": "aroma (N)",
    "examples": [
      "The aroma of fresh coffee."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8b0ba15-68d0-4cad-9eff-c67c925c59c6",
    "front": "**Def**: not having much taste. SYN bland.\n**Farsi**: بی‌مزه، بی‌طعم",
    "back": "insipid (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "This soup is insipid."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f8061c65-7af9-4b38-bf5c-c44a2a62a79c",
    "front": "**Def**: very strong smelling.\n**Farsi**: تند، زننده (بو)",
    "back": "pungent (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "Garlic has a pungent smell."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0ab009df-e316-4199-baff-1cb902700eb6",
    "front": "**Def**: smelling unpleasant or damp; without freshness. SYN dank.\n**Farsi**: کهنه، نمور، بوی گندیده",
    "back": "musty (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "The house has a musty odour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ff672a5c-7ff9-4526-8b9b-aae2834a9bde",
    "front": "**Def**: a smell, especially an unpleasant one.\n**Farsi**: بو (بوی نامطبوع)",
    "back": "odour (N)",
    "examples": [
      "The house has a musty odour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "91c25e64-ad4a-4aa2-990f-c92aa2be7e3a",
    "front": "**Def**: very unpleasant. SYN disgusting.\n**Farsi**: منزجر کننده، چندش‌آور",
    "back": "revolting (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "This fish smells revolting."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2d42eff4-33ae-413b-9a23-febaf4b5ec5d",
    "front": "**Def**: (of food and drink) go bad and be unfit to eat or drink.\n**Farsi**: فاسد شدن (غذا)",
    "back": "go off (PHR V)",
    "examples": [
      "I think it's gone off."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "affea6f1-06ac-4256-a589-0d896527036e",
    "front": "**Def**: making you feel you want to vomit.\n**Farsi**: حالت تهوع‌آور",
    "back": "nauseating (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "a nauseating stench in the basement."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c8930e6-afff-4329-96f4-745f4a1a40b7",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong, very unpleasant smell.\n**Farsi**: بوی گند، بوی تعفن",
    "back": "stench (N)",
    "examples": [
      "a nauseating stench in the basement."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "52a332f5-f681-4455-b883-94633c8822a5",
    "front": "**Def**: the skin covering the part of the head where your hair is. If it itches (or is itchy), you want to scratch it.\n**Farsi**: پوست سر خارش‌دار",
    "back": "itchy scalp",
    "examples": [
      "I had an itchy scalp until I started using this special shampoo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d5f7a874-0c4c-43dc-9ecc-d5b084056197",
    "front": "**Def**: a very bad headache.\n**Farsi**: سردرد شدید/وحشتناک",
    "back": "splitting headache",
    "examples": [
      "I've got a splitting headache."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2c80d6c3-2289-4e3b-ba52-95ea6e67361d",
    "front": "**Def**: an allergy affecting the nose, eyes, and throat, caused by pollen from plants.\n**Farsi**: تب یونجه (حساسیت فصلی)",
    "back": "hay fever",
    "examples": [
      "I suffer from hay fever in the summer."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "854f9625-4314-44ac-a0f0-849724729f0c",
    "front": "**Def**: small sore areas inside the mouth, usually lasting a few days.\n**Farsi**: آفت دهان",
    "back": "mouth ulcers",
    "examples": [
      "Why does he get mouth ulcers?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c7ca9c62-721d-48a3-97ad-1fabe8071a45",
    "front": "**Def**: put a bone out of its normal position.\n**Farsi**: در رفتن استخوان",
    "back": "dislocate sth",
    "examples": [
      "He dislocated his shoulder."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "158dfeba-76e7-4d0b-aaf1-67d03ef3723b",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of red spots on the skin, caused by an illness or a reaction to sth.\n**Farsi**: بثورات/جوش پوستی",
    "back": "rash",
    "examples": [
      "That's a nasty rash on your arm."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "caa1556d-630c-4631-87a0-c0a443edc91b",
    "front": "**Def**: unpleasant (also a nasty accident).\n**Farsi**: ناخوشایند/بد",
    "back": "nasty",
    "examples": [
      "That's a nasty rash on your arm."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "42b31110-2012-4e1e-93c0-68424844fc05",
    "front": "**Def**: a stomach problem causing sickness or diarrhoea.\n**Farsi**: ناراحتی معده",
    "back": "upset stomach",
    "examples": [
      "I had an upset stomach this morning."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1e71fd89-28c2-4e1a-a9f3-a59e09c51dca",
    "front": "**Def**: passing waste from the body too often and in liquid form.\n**Farsi**: اسهال",
    "back": "diarrhoea",
    "examples": [
      "(Implied definition)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "72608933-acc1-4f33-8350-02b86629b4ef",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to move waste material from the body. constipation N.\n**Farsi**: دچار یبوست",
    "back": "constipated",
    "examples": [
      "I often get constipated on holiday."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4630ff1e-90e7-40ef-b156-24a211cc3b39",
    "front": "**Def**: the pressure of the blood as it moves round the body. (High and low blood pressure are problem conditions.)\n**Farsi**: فشار خون بالا",
    "back": "high blood pressure",
    "examples": [
      "My mother's got high blood pressure."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1da82616-6a2f-4020-a452-217f7ed13f4a",
    "front": "**Def**: injure a part of the body (usually the wrist or ankle) by turning it suddenly.\n**Farsi**: رگ به رگ شدن/پیچ خوردن",
    "back": "sprain sth (SYN twist sth)",
    "examples": [
      "I sprained my ankle running."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "98ae9560-6831-416f-bc96-a7f4090d4880",
    "front": "**Def**: injure a muscle by stretching it too much.\n**Farsi**: کشیدگی عضله",
    "back": "pull a muscle",
    "examples": [
      "He pulled a muscle in training."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c7c03f61-ee34-4920-97e8-4dbb04df2787",
    "front": "**Def**: a sore swelling on the surface of the skin (here on the back of the foot) often caused by rubbing or burning.\n**Farsi**: تاول",
    "back": "blister",
    "examples": [
      "I've got a blister on my heel."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dbe0feae-c821-4198-8d68-3549891ece80",
    "front": "**Def**: mix a solid with a liquid until it becomes part of it.\n**Farsi**: حل کردن (در مایع)",
    "back": "dissolve sth (in sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Tablets must be dissolved in water."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "08c6d5fe-87d1-427e-9007-aed4c4d003fa",
    "front": "**Def**: (If sth is soluble it can be dissolved, e.g. soluble aspirin.)\n**Farsi**: حل شدنی",
    "back": "soluble",
    "examples": [
      "(Definition only)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fce11f19-5fc0-45fb-b3d7-4d5fb72f67d7",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of not having any energy to do things. lethargic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: بی‌حالی/کسالت",
    "back": "lethargy",
    "examples": [
      "This product can cause lethargy or drowsiness."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "551eff4f-3fc0-4ef0-8ea8-453a271f96e0",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of feeling tired and almost asleep. drowsy ADJ.\n**Farsi**: خواب‌آلودگی",
    "back": "drowsiness",
    "examples": [
      "This product can cause lethargy or drowsiness."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e612bfa6-6535-4b56-8519-32d6a72c4bd4",
    "front": "**Def**: lasting only a short period, e.g. a short-term solution. OPP long-term.\n**Farsi**: کوتاه‌مدت",
    "back": "short-term",
    "examples": [
      "For short-term use only."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7dd25d54-c4c2-4c59-a265-3fc14381001f",
    "front": "**Def**: the amount of a medicine that you take at any one time.\n**Farsi**: دوز/مقدار مصرف",
    "back": "dose (or dosage)",
    "examples": [
      "Do not exceed the stated dose."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3255970a-6826-4f3f-8dd9-db3b75139020",
    "front": "**Def**: included inside sth else, usually inside a letter or packet.\n**Farsi**: ضمیمه شده",
    "back": "enclosed",
    "examples": [
      "Please read the enclosed leaflet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6bc23e6c-6560-4e88-800a-9c35ed618ee5",
    "front": "**Def**: one or several pages of information about sth.\n**Farsi**: بروشور/راهنما",
    "back": "leaflet",
    "examples": [
      "Please read the enclosed leaflet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aaae480e-4315-4ee4-8238-6bae24f06685",
    "front": "**Def**: an extra and usually bad effect that a drug has on you.\n**Farsi**: عارضه جانبی",
    "back": "side effect",
    "examples": [
      "Possible side effects may include stomach disorders."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1ed7c94a-1f56-4ca9-8d4d-c7765e7e1bc0",
    "front": "**Def**: an illness in a part of the body.\n**Farsi**: اختلال/عارضه",
    "back": "disorder",
    "examples": [
      "Possible side effects may include stomach disorders."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fe91c19d-353f-4b28-bdd9-c57224f2ff35",
    "front": "**Def**: get rid of sth you no longer want or need.\n**Farsi**: دور انداختن",
    "back": "discard sth",
    "examples": [
      "Discard any remaining solution."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7770cff2-fd96-45c9-a9f4-eb5a6a578531",
    "front": "**Def**: continue to exist (used especially about sth unpleasant). persistent ADJ.\n**Farsi**: ادامه یافتن/باقی ماندن",
    "back": "persist (v)",
    "examples": [
      "If symptoms persist, consult your doctor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8858010-f6da-41ad-a776-79709096dc4b",
    "front": "**Def**: the date after which sth should not be used. expire v.\n**Farsi**: تاریخ انقضا",
    "back": "expiry date",
    "examples": [
      "Do not use after expiry date."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e47f47fc-4c24-42c0-8af8-461e5205f4ab",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. do more of sth than is stated in an order or a law. 2. be greater than a number, amount, or quality.\n**Farsi**: تجاوز کردن از حد/بیشتر بودن",
    "back": "exceed",
    "examples": [
      "Do not exceed the stated dose. / The film exceeded my expectations."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "85e05203-2cb9-4f0b-a2e4-ab0fa65e42e6",
    "front": "**Def**: be greater than a number, amount, or quality.\n**Farsi**: بیش از/فراتر از",
    "back": "in excess of",
    "examples": [
      "The cost won't be in excess of $5,000."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f552f01c-22be-4743-97b9-cc498a449686",
    "front": "**Def**: acting in an open and natural way, without worrying about what you say or do. spontaneity N.\n**Farsi**: خودجوش/بی‌نقشه",
    "back": "spontaneous (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm a spontaneous sort of person."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2b80cdfd-4d82-4595-af13-943f43e1dc19",
    "front": "**Def**: the quality of being spontaneous.\n**Farsi**: خودجوشی",
    "back": "spontaneity (N)",
    "examples": [
      "I think spontaneity is a positive attribute."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a2aa55f2-4868-4638-b8a5-859842b5cd50",
    "front": "**Def**: not caring or worrying about the future.\n**Farsi**: بی‌خیال/فارغ از غم",
    "back": "happy-go-lucky",
    "examples": [
      "I'm a happy-go-lucky sort of person."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c869e720-d2fd-499c-9e42-08870c2be154",
    "front": "**Def**: sensible and realistic in things you say or think.\n**Farsi**: واقع‌بین/منطقی",
    "back": "down-to-earth",
    "examples": [
      "I'm pretty down-to-earth too."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a5bb540e-0468-403e-9d64-b82b21c20a7e",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who talks a lot. chatty ADJ.\n**Farsi**: وراج/پر حرف",
    "back": "chatterbox (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "My friends say I'm a real chatterbox."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f43f2534-acf8-4c66-b02c-96f19c3cdec7",
    "front": "**Def**: very enthusiastic or interested in sth. passion (for sth) N.\n**Farsi**: پرشور/علاقه‌مند",
    "back": "passionate (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm truly passionate about people."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1a1ca1c2-d5dd-4874-97d3-f991896de2ed",
    "front": "**Def**: be prepared to try sth. SYN have a go, give sth a try.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را امتحان کردن",
    "back": "give sth a go (SYN have a go)",
    "examples": [
      "I'll give anything a go."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "38995b6a-befe-4838-984d-f8630c67afb4",
    "front": "**Def**: according to what is practical, possible, or sensible.\n**Farsi**: در حد معقول/منطقی",
    "back": "within reason",
    "examples": [
      "I'll give anything a go, within reason!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a96a525-b7a3-421a-9e9b-5fb53bd6f91a",
    "front": "**Def**: be attracted to sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: جذب چیزی/کسی شدن",
    "back": "be drawn to sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "I'm drawn to men who are considerate."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3b3777ab-6ffa-46d6-b903-709f63f85c18",
    "front": "**Def**: always thinking about other people's wishes and feelings. OPP inconsiderate.\n**Farsi**: با ملاحظه/متفکر",
    "back": "considerate (SYN thoughtful)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm drawn to men who are considerate."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c36fde28-9afb-46ff-a08c-09ebaa1721d0",
    "front": "**Def**: the feeling of liking or caring about sth/sb. affectionate ADJ.\n**Farsi**: محبت/علاقه",
    "back": "affection",
    "examples": [
      "happy to show affection."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cf3e8253-9e8c-4899-a493-bc972f75fb92",
    "front": "**Def**: the quality of being honest and having strong moral principles.\n**Farsi**: درستکاری/صداقت",
    "back": "integrity",
    "examples": [
      "A guy with integrity."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f21b4f3d-c69c-4023-a6f4-db47304f820e",
    "front": "**Def**: trying to appear important, intelligent, etc. to impress others.\n**Farsi**: متظاهر/پر ادعا",
    "back": "pretentious",
    "examples": [
      "NOT pretentious."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "201d665d-9e58-4194-8268-6e5bf480dde1",
    "front": "**Def**: a quality or feature of sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: ویژگی/صفت",
    "back": "attribute",
    "examples": [
      "spontaneity is a positive attribute."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3c3059d3-da99-44c0-8f46-0ad8669daedc",
    "front": "**Def**: = What's your impression of sb/sth?\n**Farsi**: نظر شما در مورد کسی/چیزی چیست؟",
    "back": "What do you make of sb/sth?",
    "examples": [
      "What did you make of the two candidates for the job?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dbc26ffb-5f94-48a8-9e0d-01ec06320d64",
    "front": "**Def**: An interesting or unusual person can be called a character (or a real character).\n**Farsi**: آدم خاص/فرد جالب",
    "back": "character (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Joe Pascoe was a real character."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e5d74ee1-bfaf-4b80-b856-a4959d30be1c",
    "front": "**Def**: able to think quickly; intelligent.\n**Farsi**: باهوش/حاضر جواب",
    "back": "quick-witted",
    "examples": [
      "Joe Pascoe was quick-witted, and shrewd."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a2fbe57-2de6-41b8-9885-de2d95669974",
    "front": "**Def**: good at judging people and situations.\n**Farsi**: زیرک/تیزبین",
    "back": "shrewd (SYN astute)",
    "examples": [
      "Joe Pascoe was quick-witted, and shrewd."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fa7a1a38-7732-4b6c-b655-b07029804019",
    "front": "**Def**: determined to get what you want and not caring about others.\n**Farsi**: بی‌رحم/سنگدل",
    "back": "ruthless",
    "examples": [
      "I'd say pretty ruthless too."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c4a08d8-98c6-41f7-b583-2a2feb8218c7",
    "front": "**Def**: start liking sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: از کسی/چیزی خوش آمدن",
    "back": "take to sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "I didn't take to him personally."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a826f919-d2fa-4d39-9b3b-4e0d9ad67591",
    "front": "**Def**: make a particular impression.\n**Farsi**: به نظر رسیدن/برداشت خاصی ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "come across (as)",
    "examples": [
      "He came across as rather pushy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5853eb82-cf2c-44d4-ae80-a688b6745051",
    "front": "**Def**: trying hard to get what you want, especially in a rude manner.\n**Farsi**: سمج/زورگو",
    "back": "pushy (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He came across as rather pushy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "17ff5111-43a9-4515-8bdb-b1c5981fd72a",
    "front": "**Def**: thinking you are very important, clever, etc.\n**Farsi**: خودبین/متکبر",
    "back": "conceited (DISAPPROVING)",
    "examples": [
      "a bit conceited."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b6c8769a-be62-460b-b3aa-fe620d2cdc99",
    "front": "**Def**: give sb a particular impression.\n**Farsi**: به نظر رسیدن (برداشتی ایجاد کردن)",
    "back": "strike sb (as sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Catherine actually struck me as being more suitable."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "30a5c34e-e6dd-4239-9c43-29b22864313d",
    "front": "**Def**: taking care to do things carefully and correctly.\n**Farsi**: وظیفه‌شناس/باوجدان",
    "back": "conscientious",
    "examples": [
      "She certainly seemed very conscientious."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a60be563-cca9-47fc-81cf-ef2021d34853",
    "front": "**Def**: able to be relied on as good, honest, etc.\n**Farsi**: قابل اعتماد",
    "back": "trustworthy",
    "examples": [
      "very conscientious and trustworthy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ef1a8fca-af55-4379-a2ea-8f175fad8787",
    "front": "**Def**: a quality that makes other people like you and be attracted to you. charismatic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: جذابیت/کشش",
    "back": "charisma",
    "examples": [
      "Does she have the necessary charisma?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "47997217-2540-415b-aa80-935f8dfae882",
    "front": "**Def**: behaving confidently so that people take notice of what you say.\n**Farsi**: قاطع/با اعتماد به نفس",
    "back": "assertive",
    "examples": [
      "whether she's assertive enough for this role."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "add56078-e782-4d54-9897-15229404d7a7",
    "front": "**Def**: annoy sb very much.\n**Farsi**: روی اعصاب کسی رفتن/عصبانی کردن",
    "back": "get up sb's nose (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He's not the kind of person who'd get up people's noses."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a4d8976a-57fb-4880-9cc0-748c37d0af6d",
    "front": "**Def**: when not looked at or thought about carefully.\n**Farsi**: ظاهراً/در ظاهر",
    "back": "on the surface",
    "examples": [
      "someone appears on the surface."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2e0726c8-5dc1-4347-99c9-5af74103dc24",
    "front": "**Def**: not friendly towards others.\n**Farsi**: گوشه‌گیر/فاصله‌گیر",
    "back": "aloof (SYNS distant, stand-offish)",
    "examples": [
      "A person who seems aloof."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5087eba2-b7c3-415b-a7b1-3f64ce8f8323",
    "front": "**Def**: not confident; not wanting to talk about yourself.\n**Farsi**: کمرو/متواضع",
    "back": "diffident (SYN shy)",
    "examples": [
      "may just be shy and diffident."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "245bf86c-ed37-40cc-bf0d-0bfb35c77660",
    "front": "**Def**: don't form an opinion of sth/sb by their appearance only.\n**Farsi**: از روی ظاهر قضاوت نکن",
    "back": "don't judge a book by its cover (SAYING)",
    "examples": [
      "As they say: don't judge a book by its cover."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "72f3ba61-f48e-42fd-8968-30372c26c3f9",
    "front": "**Def**: a feature of sb's character.\n**Farsi**: ویژگی/خصوصیت اخلاقی",
    "back": "trait",
    "examples": [
      "Other personality traits can be misleading."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ecdbac10-f7a0-4dea-8a1b-5e1202c656d5",
    "front": "**Def**: giving the wrong idea or impression.\n**Farsi**: گمراه‌کننده",
    "back": "misleading (SYN deceptive)",
    "examples": [
      "Other personality traits can be misleading."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eb6ea575-2f8c-4329-9fae-e5b41fbc088a",
    "front": "**Def**: a good or desirable quality. OPP vice. virtuous ADJ.\n**Farsi**: فضیلت/حسنه",
    "back": "virtue",
    "examples": [
      "being cunning, or impulsive... may be a virtue."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "19f4c7d2-2369-4dc3-995c-f3e48fbd1285",
    "front": "**Def**: able to do things by being clever, but not always honest.\n**Farsi**: حیله‌گر/زیرک",
    "back": "cunning (SYN crafty)",
    "examples": [
      "being cunning, or impulsive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bd3d4595-b8d6-4583-ae3f-1109d840bc42",
    "front": "**Def**: doing things quickly, without thinking about the results.\n**Farsi**: تکانشی/بدون فکر",
    "back": "impulsive (SYNS impetuous, rash)",
    "examples": [
      "being cunning, or impulsive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "85155b2e-c022-4f9b-82c1-923041a2ffb5",
    "front": "**Def**: lacking experience of life, and trusting others too easily. naivety N.\n**Farsi**: ساده‌لوح/خام",
    "back": "naive",
    "examples": [
      "or naive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c4540f93-9b0c-4871-a096-9ba1800e1fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb suffer because it will be good for them later.\n**Farsi**: سخت‌گیری به نفع شخص (نوعی ضرب‌المثل)",
    "back": "be cruel to be kind (SAYING)",
    "examples": [
      "sometimes you have to be cruel to be kind."
    ]
  }
]